♪ Oh, Mr. Tailor ♪
["Mr. Tailor" playing]
- ♪ Fix it ♪
- ♪ Oh, Mr. Tailor ♪
♪ Holding the scissors ♪
♪ One cut, and it's over ♪
[Lily, in English] I don't know who he is.
I told you.
[Lily, in English] I've never met him
in my entire life!
[in English] You are lying!
[Atoy, in English]
We are not working together.
[in English] Where is the laptop?
- Mmm.
- [grunts]
[Lily, in English] No, no, no, no, no!
[Audrey] You need to be taken
to the hospital. Gavin!
[Dmitri, in English] Promise me.
You won't do anything
with what you've learned.
[in English] And where is my briefcase?
- [both grunt]
- [wailing]
I'm sorry if this trip is sudden.
[Audrey] But we need to see
your Daddy Atoy first.
No one leaves.
[Red] Try to start that.
[in English] I need you
to report to me in person.
[in English] Padua is compromised.
[Audrey] We're going to see Dad
at the hospital.
Hospital, but you're bringing luggage?
You even brought this evidence
that could ruin your family.
[in English] Please.
Please, just let us go.
PREVIOUSLY
[Martina] Get a gag
and ropes for these two.
And no one should know they're here.
[Ibyang] I just want to understand her.
Does Mama have another child?
Where is she?
Sam, Sam, my child! Sam!
- [Charmi] She's your sibling.
- Sammy, Sammy!
- [Audrey wailing]
- [Mongki] Good night again.
[wailing and muttering]
[music fades]
They're secured, boss.
I made sure they're sleeping soundly.
[in English] Good.
Boss, what if Sir Dmitri comes home?
How do we explain to him that Audrey
and his grandchild are missing?
He has already arrived. I spoke to him.
I told him his precious daughter
and grandchild suddenly left,
and it looks like they're not coming back.
So, he's upset.
[Mongki] By the way, boss.
My men tracked Paldo.
They know where he's hiding.
[suspicious music playing]
Put him to sleep too.
Make sure he never wakes up.
[Mongki, in English] Copy, boss.
[line rings]
We have the go signal.
Shoot them and make sure it's clean.
[foreboding music playing]
[music fades]
[clicks tongue]
[sighs]
Life goes on. [inhales]
Life goes on.
[ominous music playing]
[tense music playing]
[both gasp]
Oh? Paldo.
What are you doing there, bro?
- Oh?
- Emerson.
Come here. What's happening to you?
Bro…
Bro, they're still chasing me.
I don't want to die yet, bro.
[in English] Please, please.
Hide me. Hide me here.
Please, I beg you, bro.
[whimpering]
Bro, they'll kill me.
- Man, they'll kill me. Please?
- [muttering]
- Please, help me.
- Yes, yes, yes. Okay, okay, okay.
- I'm scared.
- Okay, okay, okay, okay, okay.
I'll handle it, I'll handle it.
[suave theme music playing]
- Guys, guys! You know…
- [Bunda, in English] Yes?
I have a secret for you.
- What?
- Wow.
- I just want to share.
- [muttering]
I'll try a gimmick later at my eatery.
- [all] Ohh!
- Secret?
- Why did you tell us?
- Secret--
- It's a secret!
- Now we know!
- As if--
- Do you like lechon?
- Of course!
- Oh! I love that!
[muttering]
- What if you add more serving--
- [horn honking]
[squeals]
- San Antonio de Padua!
- [horn honking]
- [screaming]
- [tense music playing]
[clamoring]
[Bunda] Get back here!
- [Bunda] You don't own this road!
- Hey!
[Mona] Next time, slow down!
[ominous music playing]
[thug 1] Are you sure about this?
[thug 2] I'm sure, boss. It's here.
[gasping]
- [guns cock]
- [squeals]
[screaming and panicking]
Let's go already!
[Siony] Come on, before-- Come on, I said!
- [gunshots blasting]
- [screaming and panicking]
[molotov shattering]
[gunshots blasting]
[Emerson gasps]
- Criminals!
- [muttering]
Leave Emerson alone! [grunts]
[thug 1] Let's go! Run!
- [clattering]
- [shrieking]
- [Siony] Wait.
- [grunts]
- I'll call the police!
- Quick, sis! Call now!
[thug 2] Go!
[Bunda] Let's go attack them!
- Hurry! Attack!
- [shrieking]
[Bunda] Let's call
the fire department too!
- [shrieking]
- [Siony] Come on!
Let's get out!
What do you want?
Burn alive inside or get shot outside?!
- [coughs]
- You go first.
- [coughing]
- [fire crackling]
[music fades]
Mama, where are we going?
Shh! Can't you see I'm talking?
[phone ringing]
What?
[in English] Hello, madam.
Uh, are you on your way to the café?
Are you there already?
Oh. [titters]
[in English] I'm, I'm… I'm sorry.
I-I forgot.
Uh, what do you need?
[Martina on the phone] Money?
You got paid already, right?
Uh…
[somber music playing]
Because, um…
Can you take the child from me now?
[Olga on phone] I don't want
to do this anymore.
I'm already annoyed with her.
She's too meddlesome.
[in English] Excuse me?
[in English] You don't tell us what to do.
We'll tell you when to return the child.
[in English] So, just deal with her. Okay?
[pensive music playing]
[sighs]
Damn.
This is insane! Let's go!
Mama, wait.
Who were you talking to?
- [heavy music playing]
- [Emerson groans]
- [Paldo] Help us!
- [Emerson coughs]
- [Emerson] Help.
- [coughing]
- [people screaming outside]
[Paldo] Help us!
- [screaming]
- Oh my God! Oh, no!
- Emerson's Tailoring Shop is burning!
- [screaming]
- Emerson!
- [coughs]
[Paldo] Help us!
- My gosh! It's burning!
- Emerson, I'll save you!
Wait, wait!
- [screaming and panicking]
- Emerson!
Ah, move back!
Emong, tell them to move back!
[screaming and panicking]
[Emong] Help!
- [man 1] We need firefighters!
- [man 2] Firefighters!
- [screaming and panicking]
- [Denden] Firefighters!
- Water!
Neighbors!
I'm sure those outsiders
won't return here anymore.
After what we did?
They'll never come back!
- They're so arrogant, but no guts.
- Correct!
[phone ringing]
I'm just reminding you…
[pensive music playing]
He's Red Regalia's son.
[Cita] He's the one
who killed your father.
He already clashed with Atoy.
Who knows, maybe his dad
sent him over to spy around here?
To get revenge on Atoy.
Don't be swayed
by his smiles and cuteness,
even if he's your friend.
[phone ringing]
[T-Bak] Hey!
That's Gavin!
Why did you reject him?
[somber music playing]
[T-Bak] Rejected?
[screaming and panicking]
- Fire!
- [screaming and panicking]
[clamoring]
[woman] Fire!
[screaming and panicking]
[all] Help! Help!
[Paldo] Help! Please help us!
[screaming and panicking]
Make way! They're still inside!
Stay back!
Let me go! The fire is getting bigger!
- [Paldo] Help!
- [screaming and panicking]
[Paldo] Help!
- [Kurt] Paldo! Paldo! Paldo!
- [panicking]
- [Paldo] Help!
- [coughing]
[Kurt] Hey, hey! Wait, wait, wait, wait!
[Emerson groans]
[Kurt] Okay, okay. Go, go, go.
[Paldo] Emerson too! Ouch!
[screaming and panicking]
- Paldo!
- Brother Paldo!
[Emerson] Help! Help!
- [Kurt] Emerson!
- [Emerson] Help!
- [Kurt] Emerson! Where are you?!
- [indistinct shouting]
- [Kurt grunts]
- [Emerson coughs]
- Here, here, that's it.
- [grunts]
[Kurt, in English] I got you, bro.
- [Emong] Water!
- [Kurt] I got you. I got you!
- [coughing]
- [screaming and panicking]
- [Kurt] Okay, go.
- [Emerson] Hurry with the water!
[Kurt] Come on, come on.
I got you, I got you. There!
[music fades]
Can we watch a movie?
[scoffs] Well.
What do you think you are? Lucky?
No! Let's go home!
You'll just make me spend money.
What?
Why are you standing there?
Come on!
[pensive music playing]
Mama, I already said sorry to you.
But why do you still seem angry with me?
If I had known that toy belonged
to Sister Sammy,
I wouldn't have touched it.
Don't mention Sammy, okay.
Because you don't know her!
Do you understand?
Because you never tell me about her!
Wait. I don't understand you.
Didn't you say you wanted to be with me?
But why does it feel like you
don't want me?
[sobs]
I'm doing everything to be close to you.
Do you know why?
Huh?
Because I love Sammy more than you!
That's why I gave you away, right?
Huh? Come on! Let's go!
Come on.
- [Emerson coughs]
- [Kurt] Take him.
- [coughing]
- [screaming and panicking]
[clamoring]
Wait! Emerson!
- Emerson, Emerson!
- [screaming and panicking]
[Bunda] What do we do?!
I don't know how!
- Huh? I'll do it! I'll do it!
- [Denden] I don't know how!
I can do this. I can do this.
CPR and mouth-to-mouth resuscitation.
[music swells]
[coughs]
[exclaims]
[shrieking, laughing, cheering]
He woke up!
[T-Bak] There! The firefighters are here!
[exclaiming]
[upbeat rock music playing]
[music fades]
Ah, it hurts!
- Let's go!
- Ma, it hurts!
Stop it. Stop your crying already.
[sobbing] Mommy!
- Ma!
- Come on!
[shrieks]
It hurts!
[Olga grunts]
Why did you even come back for me?!
[melodramatic music playing]
I wish you weren't my mother!
Just give me back to Tatoy!
[sobs] You're a bad mother!
I'm not a bad mother!
I didn't want what happened!
I love Sammy so much!
Do you understand? She's my life!
Do you understand me?!
- Do you understand me?!
- [wails, then grunts]
[squeals]
[epic music playing]
[thudding]
Mama!
[music swells]
[pensive music playing]
- [tense sinister music playing]
- [Olga groans]
[Ibyang] Ma. Mama?
I'm okay.
[gasping]
Emerson, don't think about the things
you lost inside anymore.
At least nothing happened to you.
Many of us will help you out.
[somber music playing]
[indistinct chattering]
- [Mona] Who could have done that?
- [woman] It's terrible.
Sorry, bro.
[indistinct chattering]
- [woman 1] He's so handsome! Wait.
- [woman 2] Such a nice nose.
[women shrieking]
Thanks to all of you. Wait!
Ah! Have we met before?
Where?
In my dream.
[giggling, shrieking]
[Karla] Such a flirt! Wow!
He's so handsome!
Probably even more if shirtless!
- [giggling]
- Hey! Show us your abs!
Stop it!
Look at mine instead.
- Why?
- Wow! Look who's talking!
You look like Adamus,
the guardian of the water gem
in Encantadia!
- Oh, yes!
- Yes!
- [Bunda] Yes, right?
- [Mona] Doesn't he?
That's too much.
No, no. I din't look like him.
He's too handsome compared to me.
You're saying too much!
- Don't you know him?
- No. Who is he?
He's Uno Alcaraz!
[Siony] One of our
volunteer firefighters here!
- Uno!
- Volunteer!
Wow! [cheering]
Great job! Thank you!
[applauding]
[Bunda] Thank you.
So, you're a volunteer?
[in English] Yes, miss.
So, you're not a real firefighter?
Just a volunteer?
[pleasant music playing]
What do you do when there's no fire?
I'm not like regular firefighters
who are paid for their work.
Even if I'm just a volunteer,
I'm trained and reliable.
Always ready to help when there's a fire.
And if you have problems,
as long as not financial ones…
[smirks]
I'm here too.
- [Bunda] Yes!
- [Siony] Wow!
- Us, us.
- [Siony] Thank you.
- [Mona] So sweet. Thank you.
- We're always ready to help you.
But you still haven't
answered my question.
What's your job
when you're not volunteering?
[pleasant music playing]
[music fades]
[Olga moans]
[groans]
I'll do it.
[clicks tongue]
How are you, Ma?
Ouch.
- Are you hurt?
- [groans]
Ouch! [groans]
[grunts] Everything hurts.
Ouch,
Oh God.
Feels like my hips will break.
- [sighs]
- [somber music playing]
You?
Are you okay?
Weren't you hurt?
No.
You saved me.
[melancholic music playing]
You got hurt because of me.
[sighs]
[in English] Sorry.
[music fades]
Karla! What's this?
[in English] Fast Talk with Boy Abunda?
[Mona] Exactly.
Baby Uno, if a dog chased me here,
would you help me?
- Of course, definitely.
- [Bunda] Oh! He'll help you!
- Come here, come here, come here.
- [Bunda] Hey. What's that?
Ms. Karla. Right?
[pleasant music playing]
If you also want
to be a volunteer firefighter,
just tell me.
I'll help you join our team.
- [Bunda] Ah.
- Wait, wait, wait!
Why is she the only one invited?
Uh…
I mean…
all of us can be volunteers.
We don't choose.
I'll volunteer, volunteer!
I'll volunteer!
- [Siony] Stop interfering.
- [Bunda] I'll fight you for that.
Stop butting in,
because we already have a winner.
- Who?
- And that's Karla!
[teasing and cheering]
- [T-Bak] Hey, Karla!
- [Bunda] Stop it!
[teasing and exclaiming]
[somber music playing]
[alcohol spritzing]
[gasps]
Ow.
Ma, you should see a doctor.
Wait. I'll call Sister…
Uh, no need.
That's just extra expense. Sit down here.
I thought you didn't want me anymore?
Because I'm a bad mother.
I can't leave you alone.
Jeez.
I saved you,
that's why you can't leave me.
You feel guilty leaving me alone.
That's okay. I deserve it.
No.
I'm here because
you are my mama.
I felt it when
you chose to save me.
[smooching]
I'm here, Mama.
I won't leave you.
I'll watch over you.
[in English] Promise!
I won't be naughty or stubborn anymore,
so
you won't get angry.
[Olga] What the hell?!
Sammy! This is so annoying--
Didn't I tell you after playing,
you should clean up your own toys?!
What is this? You're so messy!
Oh my. This child!
Unbelievable! It even reached the table!
It's so messy.
Oh!
What is this?!
Sammy!
Why are you so dirty?!
Oh my!
If the neighbors see you, your appearance!
They'll say I'm neglecting you!
Oh!
- [somber music playing]
- [gulps]
[smooches]
Mama, I'm sorry.
Please don't be mad.
[sobs]
[Sammy] I'll fix my toys,
and I'll change my clothes.
[smooches]
Please forgive me.
[in English] Mama, sorry.
[in English] Mama, sorry. [sobs]
I didn't mean it, Mama.
[in English] Sorry.
[sobs] Please forgive me.
[sobs] Mommy.
[in English] Mama, please.
[in English] Sorry, Mama.
Stop crying, Sammy.
Mama isn't angry anymore.
[melodramatic music playing]
[sighs]
Oh, take it slowly.
[chuckles softly]
Hmm.
It's delicious.
- You're good!
- Yes!
I knew you'd like it!
One more, Mama.
Here, try the chicken.
[chuckles softly]
[pleasant music playing]
[music fades]
Ibyang.
Why are you still kind to me?
Even though…
you know, I'm a bit harsh with you.
You still didn't leave me.
Because you're my mama.
You're my family,
and with family,
no one gets left behind.
[somber music playing]
Aren't you…
curious about Sammy?
Here she is.
Her favorite dish
was adobo with coconut milk.
She didn't like candies, but…
she loved native rice cakes.
Her favorite colors…
Purple and…
sky blue.
[sobs]
She loved it when I braided her hair.
[sobbing]
Stop crying. Stop crying.
You know…
You're lucky, because…
you still got to be with her.
But me, I didn't.
But I'll behave better…
so you won't be upset with me.
I'll do everything to make you happy.
So Sister Sammy won't worry anymore.
[groans] Ouch.
[groans]
- Ma, can you stand up now?
- Oh?
Um, my hips still hurt a bit.
But don't worry.
I'm fine.
Better go upstairs.
You should rest now.
Go to sleep.
Hmm?
Yes.
But finish this, okay.
- Yes!
- Hmm.
[chuckles softly]
Go on.
[in English] Good night, Ma.
[in English] Good night, Ibyang.
[sniffles]
[sentimental music playing]
[smooches]
Careful on the stairs, okay.
Yes.
[tense music playing]
- [Janine grunts]
- Child, untie me.
- Quick, hurry. Child, child!
- [Janine panting]
[guttural cry of pain]
- [Red] What, huh?! Huh?!
- [Audrey] What will you do to her?!
- [Red] You'll escape?!
- [Audrey] Don't hurt her!
- Mommy!
- Take her!
- Let me go!
- [Audrey sobs]
- Take her!
- Enough! Let go of my child!
- Let her go!
- [Red] Take them there!
UP NEXT
[grunts]
You'll shoot me because of Audrey?
["Mr. Tailor" playing]
[in English] I will make you talk.
[in English] You see,
men like you have families.
[in English] I have men right now
searching for all of your beloved.
[in English] And I will kill every
one of them right in front of your face.
- ♪ Holding the scissors ♪
- [groans]
♪ One cut, and it's over ♪
♪ Fix this ♪
Subtitle translation by: Rachel C. Arias